♪No matter how far the road is, don’t be afraid♪
♪无论路有多远，都 不要害怕♪
♪Love is gentle and caring♪
♪爱是温柔和关怀的♪
♪Those wounds will definitely scab over♪
♪那些伤口一定会 结痂的♪
♪Everything gathers into the flower of time♪
♪一切都汇聚成时光之花♪
♪ Someone will pick it up for you eventually ♪
♪最终 会有人帮你捡的♪
♪Keep going, you won’t be alone♪
♪继续前进， 你不会孤单♪
♪Conversation with time♪
♪与时间对话♪
♪The light falls gently, just take it as her answer♪
♪光线轻轻落下， 就当作她的答案吧♪
♪May you have him in the sea of ​​people♪
♪愿你在人海中拥有他♪
♪Live a simple and peaceful life♪
♪过着 简单而平静的生活♪
♪Understand that life is full of regrets♪
♪明白人生 充满遗憾♪
♪But, you still love♪
♪但是，你依然爱着♪
♪This winter and summer♪
♪今年冬天和夏天♪
[Love is the panacea] [Episode 3]
[爱情是灵丹妙药] [第3集]
[2022 Sichuan Province Characteristic Support Artworks]
【 2022年四川省特色支持艺术品】
[Diadaptasi dari novel "Zhi Yu Zhe" karya Ning Meng Xi Yan]
[Diadaptasi dari novel "Zhi Yu Zhe" karya Ning Meng Xi Yan]
Saquon.
萨昆.
Very interesting, isn't it?
很有趣，不是吗？
this.
这。
For you.
为你。
Yeah.
呀呀。
What did you call me?
你叫我什么？
Saquon.
萨昆.
Release Dr. Gu.
释放顾医生。
Do you have a tactile disorder?
你有触觉障碍吗？
Don't like people touching you.
不喜欢别人碰你。
You talk to Saquon first.
你先和萨昆谈谈。
Tell him I want to see him.
告诉他我想看看他。
Dad, make money.
爸爸，赚钱吧。
Change?
找钱吗？
Did you teach him?
你教他了吗？
so small,
好小，
But the origin of calling people father and mother.
但称呼人为父亲、母亲的由来。
Did you teach him to slander and cheat money?
你教他诽谤 、骗钱？
What's the slander?
诽谤什么？
Growing up, no one liked Saquon.
从小到大， 没有人喜欢萨昆。
good guy for him
对他来说是个好人
Will he call mom and dad?
他会叫爸爸妈妈吗？
Such a small child
这么小的孩子
Already tainted by your madness for money.
已经被 你对金钱的疯狂所玷污了。
So what if you need change?
那如果你要找钱怎么办？
There is new money to treat disease.
有新的钱可以治疗疾病。
Sa Kun, please obey me.
萨坤，你听话。
No.
不。
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
He is afraid of injections and medicine.
他害怕打针和吃药。
Little real man.
小真男人。
You listen to your uncle.
你听叔叔的话。
now you
现在轮到你
I have to endure taking medicine every day .
每天都要忍受 吃药。
even though you are sick
尽管你生病了
There is no cure now
现在无法治愈
perhaps
或许
tomorrow or next year
明天或明年
Effective drugs will appear
有效的药物将会出现
or new treatments.
或新的治疗方法。
so,
所以，
now you have to survive
现在你必须生存
and receive treatment.
并接受治疗。
( Can all diseases really be cured?)
（ 真的所有疾病都可以治愈吗？）
In fact, there are many more uncles and aunties
其实叔叔阿姨还有很多
People who are surviving, struggling, trying.
那些在生存、挣扎、 努力的人。
So, you can't give up.
所以，你不能放弃。
You still have to fight on your own
你还得自己奋斗
and survive.
并生存下来。
enthusiasm!
热情！
Could you please translate what I just said?
你翻译一下我刚才说的话
To Saquon.
到萨昆。
what is it?
它是什么？
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
Let's translate it.
我们来翻译一下。
Saquon.
萨昆.
Let Dr. Gu check you out.
让顾医生给你检查一下。
How about I take you out to play after I check it out ?
我查完之后， 带你出去玩，怎么样？
I want to drink Coke.
我想喝可乐。
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
lie.
躺。
I said a lot before
之前说了很多话
Did you only translate a sentence or two?
你只翻译了 一两句话吗？
You are so talkative to find out.
你真是太健谈了 一探究竟。
very good.
非常好。
Saquon.
萨昆.
Once your head stops hurting
一旦你的头不痛了
Uncle will buy you a Coke.
叔叔会给你买可乐。
Thos.
托斯。
Mother An, come up quickly.
安妈妈，快上来。
let's go.
我们走吧。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
I don't want any more rumors to spread.
我不想 再有任何谣言传播。
I don't want to either.
我也不想。
I didn’t want to, but you agreed and Sakun took him to play.
本来不想，但是你答应了 萨昆带他去玩。
He is very obedient
他很听话
and want to participate in therapy.
并想参加治疗。
I can't break a promise to such a young child.
我不能违背 对这么小的孩子的承诺。
There are many children who are unwilling to participate in therapy.
有很多孩子 不愿意参加治疗。
So, do you meet all the criteria?
那么，你满足所有条件吗？
They suggest?
他们建议？
After the operation is completed,
操作完成后，
His mother never visited him in the hospital.
他的母亲从未去 医院探望过他一次。
He's still so little.
他还那么小。
he must be lonely
他一定很孤独
Very sad.
非常悲伤。
That's why you're so special to Saquon.
这就是为什么你对萨昆 如此特别。
Because you feel sorry that his mother didn't come to visit him?
因为你为他母亲没有来看望他而感到遗憾？
There are not so many reasons.
哪有那么多理由。
You are also special to Sakun .
你对Sakun也 很特别。
So, what is your reason?
那么，你的理由是什么？
There are not so many reasons.
哪有那么多理由。
Saquon.
萨昆.
Dr. Gu is very busy.
顾医生很忙。
He will stay with you all day today.
今天他要陪你一整天。
You will become rich.
你会变得富有。
so.
所以。
Make money.
挣钱。
let's go.
我们走吧。
This is luxury food
这是奢侈的食物
Did you say you wanted to eat that?
你说你想吃那个吗？
correct.
正确的。
This is the most famous culinary center of La Kaya.
这是 拉卡亚最著名的烹饪中心。
All available, all sold.
全部可用，全部出售。
Plus, everything is edible.
另外，一切都是可以吃的。
slowly.
慢慢地。
Ann's mother.
安的母亲。
There's popcorn here.
这里有爆米花。
Do you want to eat?
你想吃东西吗？
want to.
想要。
Make me pay for this.
让我为此付出代价。
careful.
小心。
Half of the exam time has passed.
考试时间已经过去一半了。
The only thing I can do is not come to the exam.
只能算是不来考试了。
Take the make-up exam next month.
下个月参加补考。
There is no remedial testing.
没有补救测试。
Must rank in the top three for eight consecutive years
必须连续八年排名前三
This will give you a chance to enter Huaren Hospital.
这样就有机会进入华仁医院。
I didn't mean to be late.
我不是故意迟到的。
I take patients to the hospital.
我带病人 去医院。
Taking patients to the hospital?
带病人去医院？
correct.
正确的。
Can anyone prove it?
有没有人可以证明一下？
(I'll prove it.)
（我会证明。）
(He was late because)
（他迟到是因为）
(Rescue patients suffering from epilepsy.)
（拯救 突发癫痫的病人。）
(So, he missed the exam time.)
（所以，他错过了考试时间。）
♪Who doesn’t feel lost in confusion? ♪
♪谁不迷失 于迷茫呢？♪
♪Find one among billions of possibilities♪
♪在数十亿种可能性中寻找一种♪
♪Trapped in a city called destiny ♪
♪被困在名为命运的都市 ♪
Saquon.
萨昆.
Are you OK?
你没事吧？
Thank you, Teacher Gu.
谢谢顾老师。
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
Why when doing everything
为什么当做每件事的时候
Like you're risking your life?
就像你冒着生命危险一样？
Before caring about others,
在关心别人之前，
Can you take care of yourself first?
你能先照顾好自己吗？
Individualistic heroism.
个人主义英雄主义。
No one told you that you are handsome?
没有人告诉过你 你很帅吗
When you don't talk?
当你不说话的时候？
Saquon.
萨昆.
Don't run.
别跑。
This is for you.
这是给您的。
What's this?
这是什么？
This is
这是
The most famous dish here is the high-protein croquettes .
这里最著名的是高蛋白炸丸子 。
Crispy and delicious.
香脆可口。
High protein croquettes?
高蛋白炸丸子？
I eat, yes.
我吃，是的。
Eat it.
吃了它。
Share the good luck.
分享好运。
you eat.
你吃。
- This is for you to eat. - you eat.
- 这是给你吃的。 - 你吃。
you eat.
你吃。
you eat first.
你先吃饭。
Exploding spiders.
炸蜘蛛。
It was so delicious.
真是太好吃了。
Your fish is cooked.
你的鱼已经煮熟了。
I told you, eat it.
我告诉过你，你吃吧。
Uh...what's wrong?
呃……怎么了？
There are ashes.
有灰烬。
Father, mother and child.
父亲、母亲和孩子。
we are not...
我们不是...
Dad, I want to eat fish.
爸爸，我想吃鱼。
I want to eat fish.
我想吃鱼。
Saquon.
萨昆.
What are you doing ? You can't call it at will.
你在干什么 不能随意调用。
I won't be fooled by you.
我不会被你愚弄。
Take your time, Saquon.
慢慢来，萨昆。
Saquon.
萨昆.
Let me check.
让我检查一下。
bad.
坏的。
Poor blood clotting.
血液凝固较差。
Once it bleeds, it cannot be stopped.
一旦流血，就无法停止。
Wear a shirt to hold it up.
穿一件衬衫来举起它。
Stop bleeding
别流血了
Don't be afraid, Saquon.
别害怕，萨昆。
Mali.
马里。
careful.
小心。
HIV positive.
艾滋病毒呈阳性。
Needs sewing.
需要缝纫。
Be prepared for protection.
做好防护准备。
Okay, I'm going to disinfect it.
好的，我去消毒一下。
Come on, let me put it on for you.
来吧，我帮你戴上。
Wear another set.
再穿一套。
I start.
我开始。
[How to help your best friend conquer the girl of your dreams? 】
【如何帮助你最好的朋友 征服你的梦中情人？】
power cut?
停电了？
Dr. Zhang.
张医生。
You just scared me!
你刚刚吓到我了！
Jiang, it’s me.
蒋，是我。
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
There's a power outage, why did you go out?
停电了， 你为什么要出去？
I happened to be writing a thesis.
我碰巧正在写论文。
The oil lamp also went out.
油灯也灭了。
The power was out, so I went outside to get some fresh air.
停电了，所以我出去呼吸 新鲜空气。
you...
你...
Why are you alone?
为什么你一个人？
Di mana Su Wei'an?
Di mana Su Wei'an?
I didn't see him all day today.
今天我一整天都没有见到他。
When I called him, his words were slurred.
给他打电话的时候， 他的话也含糊不清。
I don't know what he did.
我不知道他做了什么。
Must be looking for money.
一定是在找钱。
What can he do?
他能做什么？
What matters is that the call is connected.
重要的是呼叫已接通。
Have you not graduated with a master's degree and are already working?
你不是硕士毕业 已经工作了吗？
Why are you still writing your thesis?
你为什么还在写论文？
Academician Qiu Fazu once said,
邱法祖院士曾说过，
People who only know how to operate
只会操作的人
Refers to operating technicians.
指操作技术人员。
Medicine must master clinical practice and scientific research.
医学必须掌握 临床实践和科学研究。
Besides, following Boss these past few years,
再说了，跟随Boss 这几年，
I feel more and more that what the boss said is right.
我越来越觉得老大的话是对的。
Scientific research ability affects clinical practice thinking.
科研能力影响 临床实践思维。
If you want to realize your dream of medicine, you must learn throughout your life.
如果你想实现医学梦想， 就必须终生学习。
Why...are you looking at me like this?
为什么……你这样看着我？
I envy you.
我嫉妒你。
it is true.
是真的。
Those who have dreams will definitely shine.
有梦想的人， 一定会发光。
If you keep your word, everyone will shine.
如果你遵守你的话， 那么每个人都会发光。
Who doesn’t have dreams?
谁没有梦想？
I have no dreams.
我没有梦想。
I used to be a follower of Vian.
我曾经是维安的追随者。
Wherever he goes, I go.
他去哪儿我就去哪儿。
He is very good at learning.
他非常擅长学习。
A little whip cracks every day to push me forward.
每天都挥动着一根小鞭子 ，推动着我继续前行。
So, me too
那么，我也是
Go to a pretty good college.
去一所相当不错的大学。
He likes to study medicine,
他喜欢学医，
I also studied medicine with him.
我也跟着他学医。
But I studied zoology, which is very different from him.
不过我学的是动物学， 和他很不一样。
Not really.
并不真地。
Very.
非常。
Then,
然后，
He studied French.
他学的是法语。
I also researched it.
我也研究了一下。
However, my French is not as good as his.
然而我的法语 不如他。
after that,
在那之后，
he suddenly said
他突然说
He wants to study in France,
他想去法国留学，
go to paris
去巴黎
I'm serious this time
这次我是认真的
I can no longer accompany him.
不能再陪他了。
when i found out
当我发现
If Wei An really didn’t go to Paris
如果维安真的没有去巴黎的话
And also dropped out of school.
并且也退学了。
He gave up on the dream he had held on to for so long.
他放弃了自己坚持了这么久的梦想。
I was completely panicked.
我彻底惊慌了。
Even Wei An was willing to give up.
就连维安也愿意放弃。
What should I do?
那我该怎么办呢？
Do you think I'm disappointed?
你觉得我很失望吗？
No.
不。
Life is so long.
生命如此漫长。
One day you won't just follow.
有一天你将不再 只是跟随。
You'll know what you want to do.
你会知道 你想做什么。
However, what makes me panic
然而，是什么让我惊慌失措
It's that I don't know what I can do.
是我不知道 我能做什么。
Everyone has their own skills
每个人都有 自己的技能
and preferred areas.
和首选领域。
It's just a matter of time.
这一切只是时间问题。
For example, although Su Weian is very smart,
比如说，苏伟安虽然 很聪明，
I think
我觉得
You have advantages that he doesn't have.
你还有 他没有的优点。
What are the advantages?
有什么优点？
Try saying it.
尝试说一下。
You are good to your friends.
你对朋友很好。
What are the benefits of doing this?
这样做有什么好处呢？
I guess what you would say.
我猜你会说什么。
Of course this is an advantage.
当然这是一个优点。
There are many people who are friendly to their friends.
对朋友友善的人有很多。
However, only a few people
然而，只有少数人
He puts the interests of his friends before his own.
他将朋友的利益 置于自己的利益之上。
I remember your eyes were already red that day.
我记得那天你的眼睛已经红了。
You still don't give up on the Boss.
你仍然不放弃Boss。
You forced me
是你逼的
Go to the police station to save Su Wei'an
去警局 救苏危安
Very cool.
很酷。
In addition, I think Su Weian is also very lucky.
另外，我觉得苏唯安 也很幸运。
Because he has a friend like you.
因为他有你这样的朋友。
Your words almost made me cry.
你的话差点让我哭了。
OK
好的。
So, starting from today,
那么，从今天开始，
In my friends list,
在我的好友列表中，
Added a male friend named Fang.
补充了一位 姓方的男性朋友。
higher.
更高。
More on the right.
更多的是右边。
already.
已经。
you...
你...
Are you OK?
你没事吧？
You tripped on a flat surface
你在平坦的表面上绊倒了
Because of ataxia?
因为共济失调？
Who suffers from ataxia?
谁患有共济失调？
Hypoglycemia.
低血糖。
Is it really possible?
真的可以吗？
Are you OK?
你好吗？
Check again to see if anyone is injured.
再次检查是否有人受伤。
Are you following me?
你在关注我吗？
No.
不。
Calm down.
冷静一下啦。
There are no wounds on my body.
我的身上没有任何伤口。
We all have to take PEP medication.
我们都必须服用 PEP 药物。
I'm hungry.
我饿了。
Ayo,
阿哟，
Let's go have a meal together
我们一起去吃饭
Mali.
马里。
Taste it.
尝一下。
Came late today
今天来晚了
This is the only thing in the cafeteria.
食堂里只有这个。
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
What’s wrong with you?
你怎么了？
my father was
我的父亲曾经是
he also likes
他也喜欢
Top with two fried eggs.
上面放两个煎鸡蛋。
Your father?
你的父亲？
so...
所以...
Three years ago, he
三年前，他
Became a star in the sky.
变成了天上的一颗星星。
Is this the reason why you don't go to school?
你不去上学的原因是因为这个吗？
of course not.
当然不是。
It has nothing to do with my father.
与我父亲无关。
I just want to make money.
我只是想赚钱。
Earn more money.
赚更多的钱。
There are many opportunities for Lakaya;
拉卡亚有很多机会，
Make money fast.
快速赚钱。
Money comes from everywhere.
到处都是钱的来源。
Besides, you don't know
另外，你不知道
Europeans are very generous when it comes to giving
欧洲人在捐赠方面非常慷慨
There was no hesitation in tipping.
小费并没有丝毫犹豫。
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
Is it your family?
是你的家人吗
Are you really short of money?
真的缺钱吗？
Who would think that money is too much?
谁会觉得 钱太多了？
People who value money so much...
这么看重金钱的人...
You can save people by postponing final exams.
你可以推迟期末考试 来救人。
you can help others
你可以帮助别人
Almost considered a murderer.
几乎被认为是杀人犯。
Do you believe?
你相信吗？
Anyway, I don’t believe it.
反正我是不信。
Make money while studying medicine
一边赚钱一边学医
I choose to make money.
我选择赚钱。
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
Did you make a lot of money in Lakaya?
你 在拉卡亚赚了很多钱吗？
So much so that it helps Saquon pay for his medical bills.
以至于可以帮助萨昆 支付医疗费用。
I'm like, why are you so confused?
我想， 你为什么这么困惑？
Guru teacher.
古鲁老师。
you...
你...
Do you support Darwin's theory of evolution?
你支持 达尔文的进化论吗？
Do you mean...
你指的是...
Living things compete for survival,
生物为了生存而竞争，
The survival of the ruler.
统治者的生存。
The defective gene must be removed naturally.
有缺陷的基因 必须自然去除。
I only believe
我只相信
About the Hippocratic Oath.
关于希波克拉底誓言。
Maintain respect and treatment wherever possible
尽可能保持尊重和待遇
For every life.
为了每一个生命。
so you
那么你
Never experienced a moment of despair
从未经历过任何 一刻的绝望
In what areas are the patients you are treating not getting better?
您正在治疗的患者在哪些方面 没有好转？
We as doctors have no right to despair.
我们作为医生 没有权利绝望。
us
我们
Must survive to the end.
必须生存到最后。
Can not give up.
不能放弃。
All because of you.
全都是因为你。
Who asked you to chat with me for so long?
谁让 你陪我聊这么久的？
There is no one in the cafeteria now.
现在食堂里一个人也没有。
Who makes dinner?
谁做晚饭？
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Can't let anyone see us together.
不能让任何人 看到我们在一起。
Why can't you just let nature take its course?
为什么你不能顺其自然
Does anyone else see us together?
其他人看到我们在一起吗？
Yes, why?
是的，为什么？
What are you guilty of?
你对什么感到内疚？
I've been hiding
我一直躲着
Now that it's out, it's really weird.
现在它出来了，确实很奇怪。
Not even a ghost.
连一个鬼魂都没有。
look.
看。
There is a boss.
有一个老板。
boss.
老板。
Doctor Gu, why are you here too?
顾医生，你怎么也来了？
I...I'm hungry.
我……我饿了。
Who eats noodles with you?
谁和你一起吃面条？
Where is that person?
那个人在哪里？
nobody.
没有人。
only myself.
只有我一个人。
So why are there two bowls of noodles?
那为什么会有两碗面呢？
I want to eat two bowls of noodles.
我想吃两碗面。
Isn't it possible?
难道不可能吗？
Have you used these two pairs of chopsticks ?
这两双筷子 已经用过了吧？
I like
我喜欢
A bowl and a pair of chopsticks.
一个碗 配一双筷子。
Isn't it possible?
难道不可能吗？
able.
能。
boss.
老板。
Where are you going today?
今天你要去哪里？
It seems this is the first time
看来这是第一次
Were you on vacation after coming here?
你来这里之后是在度假吧？
I haven't seen you all day, I'm so...
一整天没见到你了， 我很...
I'm not used to this.
我对此很不习惯。
Me too.
我也是。
I didn't see Wei An all day.
我一整天都没有见到维安。
I'm not used to it either.
我也不习惯。
boss.
老板。
you...
你们...
Why us?
为什么是我们？
I'm not with Su Wei'an.
我没有和苏薇安在一起。
It’s rare to have an afternoon break
难得有一个下午的休息时间
So just take a walk.
所以就散散步吧。
Boss, I didn’t ask you and Su to translate.
老大，我也没问 你和苏翻译。
Let me ask you and translator Jiang,
我问你和姜译者，
Would you like to eat scallion pancakes or dumplings?
你想吃 葱油饼还是饺子？
I eat noodles.
我吃面条。
Take a seat, Jiang.
坐吧，蒋。
I made scallion pancakes for you.
我给你做了葱油饼。
Doctor Gu.
顾医生。
Are you OK?
你没事吧？
Why do I feel like you look nervous?
为什么我感觉 你看起来很紧张？
I...I'm not nervous.
我……我不紧张。
Am I nervous?
我紧张吗？
No.
不。
good smell.
很香。
Mari, cicipi. Jiang Muying.
Mari, cicipi. Jiang Muying.
Scallion pancakes made by the aunt in the cafeteria
食堂阿姨做的葱油饼
very delicious.
非常美味。
what time is it?
现在是几奌？
Why do you think Wei An hasn’t come home yet?
你觉得 维安为什么还没有回家？
Why haven't you gone home yet?
你怎么还没回家？
You contact him.
你联系他。
If you can't,
如果你不能，
I'll accompany you to pick him up.
我陪你去接他。
What is that sound?
那是什么声音？
That's...my text message.
那是……我的短信。
short message.
短消息。
It's hot.
很热。
I am too careless.
我太粗心了。
just me.
只有我。
Not hot either.
也不热。
My hands are relatively sensitive.
我的手比较敏感。
Jiang Muying.
Jiang Muying.
Su Wei'an is becoming more and more courageous, isn't he?
苏危安的胆子是越来越大了不是吗？
You dare to go out alone at this time of night .
深夜这个时候 你也敢一个人出去。
Has General Kouyate's anger subsided?
库亚特将军的怒火 平息了吗？
so...
所以...
bad.
坏的。
The phone only rang once and then turned off, right?
手机只响了一声 就关机了是吗？
So, he couldn't have been captured by General Kouyate, right?
那么，他不可能是 被库亚特将军俘虏的吧？
cannot. I had to... I had to look for it.
不能。 我必须……我必须寻找它。
Fang Mingfan.
Fang Mingfan.
Jiang Muying went out alone at night
江暮影 晚上一个人出去了
Go find Su Wei'an.
去找苏危安。
Lakaya is too dangerous
拉卡亚太危险了
Are you calm?
你冷静吗？
Wait for me, Jiang.
等我一下，江。
Why do you want to scare Jiang?
你为什么要吓唬蒋？
He really came out to me.
他真的出来找我了。
If I don't kick him out
如果我不把他赶出去
Do you still have a chance to blame me now ?
现在你还有机会责怪我吗 ？
You call him quickly.
你赶紧给他打电话。
It can also call him back.
它还可以叫他回来。
This is also true.
这也是对的。
Hello, Teacher Jiang.
江老师你好。
I...
我...
I am fine.
我很好。
Just on the road
就在路上
Meet old customers
认识老客户
and had dinner with him. that's right.
并与他共进晚餐。 这是正确的。
I'm back.
我回来了。
Wait for me in the room.
在房间里等我。
Until it was discovered.
直到被发现。
I go first.
我先走了。
slowly.
慢慢地。
[Moutai buying price (official) 42,710 francs, selling price 100 US dollars/600 yuan]
【茅台买入价（官方）42,710法郎 卖出价100美元/600人民币】
[The first million dollar financial plan]
[首个百万美元理财计划]
[CITIC Bank interest rate 1.95; Shanghai Pudong Development Bank interest rate 1.55]
【中信银行利率1.95； 浦发银行利率1.55]
Why don't you look at other people's stuff carefully?
你为什么不小心 看别人的东西？
I don't know whose it is.
我不知道是谁的。
If you don't know who it is from , you shouldn't watch it.
如果你不知道是谁的 ，你就不应该看。
Don't know whose it belongs to
不知道是谁的
So you have to look at who it actually belongs to
所以你必须看看 它实际上属于谁
Return it to its owner.
将其归还给它的主人。
Then, what did you see?
然后，你看到了什么？
What did I see?
我看到了什么？
I see other people 's obsession with making money.
我看到别人 对于赚钱的执着。
And the ability to calculate everything.
还有计算一切事物的能力。
Before the age of 60,
60岁之前，
He absolutely can
他绝对可以
A very wealthy money maniac.
一个非常富有的金钱狂。
Su Wei'an,
Su Wei'an,
I started to really believe it
我开始真正相信它
You would give up studying medicine to make money.
你会为了赚钱而放弃学医。
only,
只是，
The life of a man who gave up his dreams for money ,
一个为了金钱而放弃 自己梦想的人的生活，
Is it a bit weak?
是不是有点弱了？
Right in the operating room,
就在手术室里，
You just hold up the light like this,
你就这样举起灯，
At first glance I thought
我乍一看以为
You are one of our members.
你是我们的会员之一。
Su Wei'an, what are you thinking about?
苏危安， 你到底在想什么？
I remember when you saw the stars I said
我记得 当你看到星星时我说
Starlight is so heartbreaking...
星光太让人心碎了..
like the memories left behind
就像留下的回忆
The dead are in the hearts of the living.
死者 在生者心中。
However, I think
然而，我反而认为
Even if you are destined to die,
即使注定要死，
stars will stay
星星将会留下
Devoted to his last labors,
致力于他最后的辛劳，
His last strength,
他最后的力量，
Leave the brightest light in the dark sky.
在黑暗的天空中留下最亮的光。
Just like every one of us.
就像我们每个人一样。
Each of us is destined to die.
我们每个人都注定要死。
However, our values ​​exist in this world
然而，我们的价值观存在于这个世界上
Like the light of those stars,
就像那些星星的光一样，
Can shine forever.
可以永远闪耀。
What Teacher Gu said is true.
顾老师的话是真的。
However, maybe I will disappoint Master Gu.
不过，或许我要让 顾大师失望了。
Making money is my whole dream.
赚钱是 我全部的梦想。
In addition, I also hope to borrow the blessing of Teacher Gu,
除此之外，我也希望 借古老师的加持，
I can live to be 60 years old in frail condition.
我可以虚弱地活 到60岁。
Are you back already?
已经回来了吗？
You must be very tired, right?
你一定很累吧？
Mali,
马里，
I'll give you a massage.
我给你按摩。
Mali.
马里。
What, this power?
怎么，这力量？
Yes.
是的。
Really comfortable.
真的很舒服。
Come out and take me.
出来带我吧。
Too much?
太多了？
I can still help you share some of the burden.
我还是可以 帮你分担一些负担的。
This includes evening snacks.
其中包括晚间小吃。
I know you moved me for no more than three seconds.
我知道你感动我的时间 不超过三秒钟。
today,
今天，
If I hadn’t met Dr. Gu in the cafeteria,
如果不是在食堂遇见顾医生，
I thought you two went out together.
我以为你们两个一起出去了
how so?
怎么会这样？
He doesn't like me, you know?
他不喜欢我，你知道吗？
I have no idea.
我不知道。
I even feel it
我什至感觉到了
You are very capable of stimulating his emotions.
你很有能力激发他的情绪。
Isn't this a special kind of existence?
这难道不是 一种特殊的存在吗？
include.
包括。
Very special.
非常特别。
This is really special.
这真的很特别。
no.
不是。
You didn't see him today.
今天你没有看到他。
Tonight, he is
今晚，他是
Looking so lonely and weak.
看起来是那么的孤独和虚弱。
Looks very thirsty for love.
看起来非常渴望爱情。
Very.
非常。
why me...
为什么是我...
I mean,
我是说，
How can you see it?
你怎么能看到它？
very clear.
非常清楚。
you think,
您认为，
a normal adult man
一个正常的成年男子
So cold and firm,
如此冰冷而坚定，
In the cafeteria at midnight
半夜在食堂
Cook two bowls of noodles.
煮两碗面条。
Still use two pairs of chopsticks.
仍然使用两双筷子。
It turns out
事实证明
He is waiting for the person to eat noodles with him.
他在等那个 和他一起吃面条的人。
Don't you feel it?
你没感觉到吗？
Very sensitive?
非常敏感？
Is it moving?
它在动吗？
Why do I feel so sick?
为什么我感觉这么恶心？
Su Wei'an.
Su Wei'an.
You've learned to be stupid, haven't you?
你已经学习到傻了，不是吗？
I don’t understand the romance of life.
不懂生活的浪漫。
Jiang.
蒋.
Gu Yunzheng,
Gu Yunzheng,
He is so great,
他是如此伟大，
But still single.
但仍保持单身。
do you think it's because
你认为因为
Didn't he find anyone to eat noodles with him?
没找到人陪 他吃面吗？
so...
所以...
He's too arrogant
他太嚣张了
In his eyes, apart from medicine
在他眼里，除了医学之外
Absolutely nothing else.
绝对没有别的。
Your words are exactly the same as Fang Mingfan's.
你的话和方明凡一模一样。
Fang Mingfan still said
方明凡依然说道
Gu Yunzheng's partner is
顾允正的搭档是
Cushing. You know that, right?
库欣。你知道，对吧？
What does this prove?
这证明了什么？
This proves that you know Gu Yunzheng very well.
这证明 你太了解顾云铮了。
You two weren't close, but you understood him.
你们两个关系并不亲密， 但你理解他。
perhaps
或许
he is
他是
Is this special being waiting for you?
这个特殊的存在在等你吗？
According to me.
据我说。
Jiang.
蒋.
Do you know what part of you I envy the most ?
你知道我最羡慕你的哪一部分吗 ？
What?
什么？
I envy your rich imagination.
羡慕你想象力丰富。
I'll give you a start,
我会给你一个开始，
You can create something world-famous.
你可以创造出 世界闻名的作品。
Doctor Gu, please save him.
顾医生，请救救他。
Translator Su has no money to pay the fine.
苏翻译自己没钱 交罚款，
But I have money to pay my neighbor’s medical bills.
但有钱支付 邻居的医疗费。
This neighbor is not simple, yes.
这个邻居不简单，是的。
Did you make a lot of money in Lakaya?
你 在拉卡亚赚了很多钱吗？
So much so that it helps Saquon pay for his medical bills.
以至于可以帮助萨昆 支付医疗费用。
Father, mother and child.
父亲、母亲和孩子。
we are not...
我们不是...
Dad, I want to eat fish.
爸爸，我想吃鱼。
I want to eat fish.
我想吃鱼。
Saquon.
萨昆.
What are you doing ? You can't call it at will.
你在干什么 不能随意调用。
[Kota Jinhai, Farmasi Jiehui]
[Kota Jinhai, Farmasi Jiehui]
Regular use of a brain pacemaker
经常使用脑起搏器
[CEO Du Yuncheng] used for neurodegenerative diseases.
【CEO杜云成】 用于神经退行性疾病。
including Parkinson's disease,
包括帕金森病，
Huntington's disease, etc.
亨廷顿舞蹈症等。
Is Wei An very busy recently?
维安最近很忙吗？
He hasn't been here for a month.
他已经一个月没来了。
Pu Du.
朴杜.
Professor Wen called and said
温教授打电话说
You have not asked Finance to allocate project funds
您还没有要求财务 划拨项目资金
It should be coming this month.
这个月应该会到来。
This HDQ39 project
这个HDQ39项目
We have been investing for more than two years.
我们已经投资 两年多了。
Development is very slow.
发展非常缓慢。
The money invested did not yield the slightest profit.
投入的钱 没有得到丝毫的利润。
After I saw it,
我看到之后，
The number of people living with this rare disease nationwide
全国患有这种罕见疾病的人数
Only thirty thousand people remained.
只剩下三万人了。
Although our drug has already been IPO,
虽然我们的药已经IPO了，
Where does the profit come from?
利润从何而来？
The return on investment is too low.
这个投资回报率 太低了。
Manager Chen.
陈经理。
What is the purpose of Jiehui Company?
杰辉公司的宗旨是什么？
Our profit target for this year
我们今年的盈利目标
It should be double what it was last year.
应该是去年的两倍。
Jika HDQ39
吉卡HDQ39
Can cure Huntington's disease,
可以治愈亨廷顿氏舞蹈病，
It is definitely a major event that caused an uproar in the global medical community.
肯定是一件 引起全球医学界轩然大波的大事件。
This could kick-start Jiehui's plans for an initial public offering.
这可能会启动杰​​辉的首次公开募股计划。
Any small amount of money lost by the patient
患者损失的任何少量金钱
Can be withdrawn from the stock market.
可以 从股市收回。
Don't just look at the little money in front of you.
不要只看 眼前的一点点钱。
correct.
正确的。
Mr. Du's vision is broader.
杜先生的视野更广阔。
I'm the one who lacks consideration.
我就是那个缺乏考虑的人。
If so, I would immediately go and urge the finance department.
如果是这样，我会立即去 催促财务部门。
OK
好的。
grandfather.
爷爷。
This is the medicinal wine my mother gave you .
这是我母亲给你的药酒 。
grandfather.
爷爷。
This is Jiehui’s financial report last year.
这是杰辉去年的财务报告。
Last year, Jiehui totaled
去年，杰辉总计
Introducing 12 categories of medical devices.
介绍12类医疗器械。
In terms of scientific research...
在科学研究方面...
This Clivia
这君子兰
No flowers either.
也不开花。
grandfather.
爷爷。
Clivia doesn't like water.
君子兰不喜欢水。
Just water once a week.
每周浇一次水就可以了。
It causes the buds to split.
它会导致 花蕾分裂。
grandfather,
爷爷，
You poured too much water.
你倒的水太多了。
So that’s it, yes.
原来是这样，是啊。
Jiehui ini
Jiehui ini
Even though it was founded after I retired,
尽管它是在我退休后创立的，
But I founded this company
但我创立了这家公司
don't want more
不再想要更多
Sold some useful patents I owned .
卖掉了我拥有的一些有用的专利 。
If it weren't for three years ago
如果不是三年前
You 've wanted to take over the company since you were a kid,
你从小 就想接管公司，
There will be no such development.
也不会有 这样的发展。
Because the company has been handed over to you,
因为公司 已经交给你了，
There are some things you don't need to tell me.
有些事情 你不需要告诉我。
up to you.
自己决定。
Thank you, grandpa.
谢谢你，爷爷。
It's getting late, go home and rest.
时间不早了，回家休息吧。
Oh yes. Take away the medicinal wine.
哦是的。将药酒收走。
What matters is that people come.
重要的是人来了。
Zheng.
郑。
able.
能。
It’s been over a year since you went to Lakaya.
你去拉卡亚已经一年多了。
Are you satisfied with that place?
看到那个地方还满意吗？
If so, then go home.
如果是这样，那就回家吧。
I know, Grandpa.
我知道，爷爷。
[Lakaya]
[拉卡亚]
This aid is still available for two months.
这项援助 还有两个月的时间。
Once the time is right,
一旦时机成熟，
I will go home.
我会回家。
OK
好的。
Grandpa is waiting for you.
爷爷正在等你。
You have to take care of your health.
你必须照顾你的健康。
Grandpa is the same, take good care of your body.
爷爷也一样，照顾好自己的身体。
See you later.
那么一会儿见。
Until it was discovered.
直到被发现。
[Kota Jinhai]
[Kota Jinhai]
Mother
母亲
You're home, right?
你到家了，对吧？
how?
如何？
Today, I will report the company’s situation to my grandfather.
今天一边 向爷爷汇报公司的情况，
Did grandpa praise you?
爷爷夸奖你了吗？
During your three years as CEO,
在您担任首席执行官的三年里，
Jiehui profit growth rate
杰辉利润增长率
is the highest
是最高的
Across pharmaceutical companies.
跨制药公司。
Grandpa said,
爷爷说，
You must use red Ganoderma lucidum or purple Ganoderma lucidum to make wine.
酿酒必须使用 红灵芝或紫灵芝，
Not black reishi.
不是黑灵芝。
The effect of soaking black Ganoderma lucidum is not as good as eating mushrooms.
泡黑灵芝的效果 不如吃蘑菇。
Mother
母亲
You don't have to bother doing this next time.
下次您无需 再费心这样做。
My hands were split when I washed Ganoderma lucidum last time.
上次洗灵芝的时候手裂了。
grandfather
爷爷
I can take care of it.
我可以照顾它。
It's important that you take care of yourself
重要的是你要照顾好自己
And dad's health, that's enough.
还有爸爸的健康，这就足够了。
what are you saying?
你在说什么？
This is all my best intention.
这一切都是我的好意。
After your grandfather retired,
你爷爷退休后，
He likes to collect medicinal wine and the like.
他喜欢收集一些药酒 之类的东西。
If it weren't for him not letting me enter the old house
如果不是他不让我 进老房子
Do I need to ask you to get it for me?
我需要请你 帮我拿吗？
Dad, I'm back.
爸爸，我回来了。
Arrive home already?
已经到家了吗？
Your mother said your company's annual report is good.
你妈妈说你们公司的年报 不错。
very good.
非常好。
Thank you dad.
谢谢爸爸。
Such beautiful hands,
如此美丽的双手，
Not holding a scalpel.
没有拿着手术刀。
Why does it grow on your body?
为什么它会长在你的身上？
This is very unfortunate.
这是非常不幸的。
Pharmaceutical companies can both cure diseases and save lives.
制药公司既可以治病 ，也可以救人。
Oh yes.
哦是的。
Your brother's term of service is coming to an end.
你哥哥的服务期限即将结束。
Have you called him?
你给他打过电话了吗？
Did he say when he planned to come home?
他有说过 他打算什么时候回家吗？
You and Yun are my sons, Du Yongsong.
你和云正是 我的儿子杜永松。
We are a family.
我们是一家人。
To be proactive, one should be the proactive person.
要说主动， 就应该是主动的人。
You should pay attention to him too.
你 也应该关注他。
You're a big brother, right?
你是个大哥哥，对吧？
It’s not like you don’t know Yunzheng’s character.
你又不是不知道云正的性格。
When will he come home?
他什么时候回家，
Who will tell Yun Cheng?
谁会告诉云城？
He can't even see your WeChat.
他连你的微信都看不到。
Searching in Cloud City,
云城寻觅，
Isn’t it also wasteful?
不是也很浪费吗？
Dad, Mom, I still have a project book to read.
爸爸、妈妈，我还有一本项目书 要看。
I'll go up first.
我先上去吧。
Go to bed early and don't stay up late.
早点休息， 不要熬夜。
You should also go to bed early.
你们也早点休息吧。
Wei'an.
Wei'an.
I love you for a long time.
我喜欢你很久了。
Do you want to date me?
你想和我约会吗？
accept!
接受！
[Library] Accepted!
[图书馆]
why go
为什么要去
What a pity.
太可惜了。
[Wen Ran]
[Wen Ran]
♪The night clock continues to tick♪
♪夜晚的时钟继续滴答作响♪
♪The noise slowly replaced the silence♪
♪喧闹慢慢 取代了寂静♪
♪We are performing a meeting script♪
♪我们正在表演 会议剧本♪
♪The night is filled with rainbows♪
♪夜晚洒满彩虹♪
♪With the wind blowing across the desert♪
♪伴随着吹过沙漠的风♪
♪All this is our testimony♪
♪这一切都是我们的见证♪
♪Who doesn’t feel lost in confusion? ♪
♪谁不迷失 于迷茫呢？♪
♪Find one among billions of possibilities♪
♪在数十亿种可能性中寻找一种♪
♪Trapped in a city called destiny ♪
♪被困在名为命运的都市 ♪
♪However, let’s chase stars♪
♪不过，还是追星吧♪
♪Don't worry, people will lose the direction of what I love♪
♪别担心， 人们会迷失我所爱的方向♪
♪Hold a glass of wine to warm your lonely soul♪
♪捧一杯酒， 温暖孤独的灵魂♪
♪Let me hug your scars♪
♪让我拥抱你的伤疤♪
♪You shine like a star♪
♪你像星星一样闪耀♪
♪Sparkle when you are alone♪
♪孤独时闪闪发光♪
♪The night clock continues to tick♪
♪夜晚的时钟继续滴答作响♪
♪The noise slowly replaced the silence♪
♪喧闹慢慢 取代了寂静♪
♪We are performing a meeting script♪
♪我们正在表演 会议剧本♪
♪The night is filled with rainbows♪
♪夜晚洒满彩虹♪
♪With the wind blowing across the desert♪
♪伴随着吹过沙漠的风♪
♪All this is our testimony♪
♪这一切都是我们的见证♪
♪Who doesn’t feel lost in confusion? ♪
♪谁不迷失 于迷茫呢？♪
♪Find one among billions of possibilities♪
♪在数十亿种可能性中寻找一种♪
♪Trapped in a city called destiny ♪
♪被困在名为命运的都市 ♪
♪However, let’s chase stars♪
♪不过，还是追星吧♪
♪Don't worry, people will lose the direction of what I love♪
♪别担心， 人们会迷失我所爱的方向♪
♪Hold a glass of wine to warm your lonely soul♪
♪捧一杯酒， 温暖孤独的灵魂♪
♪Let me hug your scars♪
♪让我拥抱你的伤疤♪
♪You shine like a star♪
♪你像星星一样闪耀♪
♪Sparkle when you are alone♪
♪孤独时闪闪发光♪